The American saga begins this summer.
Horizon: An American Saga - Chapter 1 is a western,
drama film directed by Kevin Costner.
In 1859, families discover the lure of the Old West as they
settle in territories from Wyoming to Kansas.
Meanwhile, a gruff cowboy finds himself on the run with a
prostitute and a young boy after killing a fellow gunman.
Hayes Ellison, played by Kevin Costner.
Frances Kittredge, played by Sienna Miller.
Trent Gephart, played by Sam Worthington.
'Ellen' Harvey, played by Jena Malone.
Marigold, played by Abbey Lee.
Sgt. Major Thomas Riordan, played by Michael Rooker.
Horizon: An American Saga – Chapter 1 is a 2024 American epic Western film directed and produced by Kevin Costner
from a screenplay he co-wrote with Jon Baird, based on an original story by the pair and Mark Kasdan.
The first installment in the titular film series, it stars an ensemble cast including Costner, Sienna Miller, Sam Worthington, and Giovanni Ribisi, with Jena Malone, Abbey Lee, Michael
Rooker, Danny Huston, Luke Wilson, Isabelle Fuhrman, Jeff Fahey, Will Patton, Tatanka Means, Owen Crow Shoe, Ella Hunt, and Jamie Campbell Bower co-starring in supporting roles.
The film follows several characters navigating life in the
Midwestern territories amid the American Civil War.
Costner conceived the idea for an epic Western film in 1988, but it
languished in development hell for three decades.
The film was finally confirmed in January 2022 with Costner as director, with an original plan to shoot the
first two films of an envisioned four-film saga back-to-back and release them digitally on HBO Max.
Much of the cast signed on in August, with filming beginning
that month in Utah and lasting through November.
The first two films carry a reported combined budget of $100
million, of which $38 million Costner personally funded.
Chapter 1 premiered at the 77th Cannes Film Festival on May 19, 2024, and
was theatrically released in the United States on June 28.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and underperformed at
the box-office, grossing only $38.7 million worldwide.
The film was filmed back-to-back with a sequel, Chapter 2, which had its world premiere at the 81st Venice International
Film Festival, and was scheduled to be released in August 2024 but had not been released as of December 2025.
Chapter 3 started filming in May 2024, while Chapter 4 is in development.
The film explores themes of montana, indigenous,
brothel, new mexico, american civil war.
The tone is emotional.